(226) 507-9449 Ontario, Canada tylerburleigh@gmail.com

Tyler Burleigh

Data Scientist

github.com/tylerburleigh linkedin.com/in/tylerburleigh

I'm an experienced data and research scientist, having worked in academia for more than 10 years and in industry at health-tech and ed-tech startups for more than 7 years. I'm passionate about applying research and data science to improve decision-making at organizations that want to help people and improve society.

SKILLS

Languages R, Python, SQL

Packages dplyr, ggplot2, tidymodels, pandas, statsmodels, sklearn, plotly
Tools Databricks, Snowflake, dbt (ETL), Segment (events), Periscope (BI)

Skills Causal inference, experiments and quasi-experiments, functional programming, data visualization, sta-

tistical modeling and machine learning algorithms (e.g., regressions, decision trees)

EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist / Data Scientist II

Prodigy Education

Jun. 2020 — Present

Oakville, Ontario

- Supported Educator product teams with the release of new features in the Teacher App, through experiments, metrics, data models, dashboards, and quantitative user research.
- Conducted exploratory quantitative user research to identify new opportunities and inform Educator product roadmaps.
- Provided mentorship to junior Data colleagues through supervision and the development of team processes and best practices.

Data ScientistNov. 2018 — Mar. 2020Clover HealthJersey City, New Jersey

- Supported the research, design, and measurement of customer-facing behavioural science campaigns aimed at driving customer retention and improved patient health outcomes.
- Developed algorithms for campaign eligibility and prioritization.
- Designed, analyzed, and interpreted over 25 behavioral science experiments.

Research Scientist

Datacubed Health

New York, New York

- Developed and empirically validated psychometric instruments for the Datacubed mobile app.
- Managed a longitudinal mobile research study with 60 participants.
- Lead the development of an app prototype called "ResQ", which was a finalist in the 2018 Robert Wood Johnson Foundation
 Opioid Challenge.

Assistant Research Scientist

New York University

Mar. 2017 — Dec. 2017

New York, New York

• Managed the selection, implementation, and empirical validation of 100+ mobile app-based psychological instruments.

EDUCATION

| PhD in Applied Cognitive Science, University of Guelph | 2017 |
|---|------|
| Awarded the John Vanderkamp Doctoral Graduate Medal as the top student in my cohort | |
| MA in Cognitive Psychology, Carleton University | 2011 |
| BA in Psychology (Comp. Sci Minor), Bishop's University | 2009 |
| Awarded the Certificate of Academic Excellence from the CPA | |
| Continuing Education | |
| - Tensorflow in Practice, Coursera | 2020 |
| - Data Scientist with Python, Datacamp | 2019 |
| - Data Science Specialization, Coursera | 2019 |

ACTIVITIES

Freelance software development and analytics to support eMERGE Guelph's Home Tune-Up program Developed pyMTurkR, an R package to interface with Amazon MTurk's Requester API Board of Directors and Treasurer, Ontario Public Interest Research Group (OPIRG) Guelph

2016 — Present Jun. 2019 — Sept. 2019 Jun. 2012 — Mar. 2015